[music]
[Instructor] So we've gotten to move
around our
Animator window just a little bit.
And we've gotten to go,
and look into
some of the animations themselves,
and preview them.
And we've seen some of the movement
between all of the transitions.
So now what we're going to do is
we're actually going to play around
with the values
in these transitions.
So knowing that our transition
for our "Speed"
needs to greater than .25
to be able to start
this "Walk_Static" animation,
we can actually go
over on the left side
of the Animator window
to Parameters.
And if we click this tab,
we have a Parameter section that opens.
And here you can actually see
the Parameter of the Speed...
that we can set. So in fact,
if we make this for example .3
because .3 is greater than .25,
and now when we press Play in our game,
we can actually see
when the Player enters the game,
then it should go into the "Idle" state,
and then it'll go down
to the Walk_Static state.
So we're an in Idle,
and then it starts Walking.
Now, it looks a little weird,
because the Background
is moving incredibly fast compared
to the actual Player.
So let's see what kinda speed
that we need to have.
We need greater than .5,
so we'll make this...
we'll just make this 1.
So that's definitely,
definitely more than .5.
So we press Play.
There you go. And then you can
see it goes from the Walking
to the running animation.
Now that does look kinda weird
because the scene is just moving,
so we can actually
set a default animation state.
So if we go to our "Run_Static" here,
and we right click on it,
we can actually
"Set as Layer Default State."
So if we select that,
you can see our entry state
goes directly to our Run_Static
instead of to Idle because from Idle,
we had to go to Walk_Static
all the way to Run_Static,
and that just took way too long.
So now when we press Play,
you can see that the Player
starts running.
The animation's still
a little too slow,
but we can fix that really easily.
So you can see on our
different states
there's actually some information
in the Inspector.
So you can see actually, the Speed
of which the animation runs.
So since the Player looked like
they were running a little slow,
comparatively we'll set
this to something like 1.5.
And now we'll Play this animation.
And there you go, now it looks
like the Player's really running,
and then they jump, and they're still
running. But that's fine,
we can fix that at some point.
Now they're just moving so fast
that they just end up back
in the same place on earth.
And then one more thing
that you can see
is you can actually see different
animation Layers which we'll go into.
But it's just kind of interesting
to see how they all work.
So with the Idle, you know,
you can see all of these different
Idle states that it can go into.
With jumping, you can go from Idle
to a "Standing_Jump"
or "Walk," and then "Walking_Jump."
There's different ways
of dying, or crouching.
So there's all of these different kinds
of animation states that we can control,
based on certain conditions.
So what you're going to do
is you're going to start using
some animations of your own.
So make sure that you click
on the Player in the Hierarchy.
In their Animator Component,
you're going to double-click
on the Controller
which will then open up
your Animator window.
In your Animator window,
you're going to move
with either alt and left clicking,
or pressing down your mouse wheel,
and dragging around.
You're going to find Run_Static,
right click on it,
set it as the default Layer state.
And then in your Parameters,
you're going to set
your "Speed_f" to 1.
And then inside
of your Inspector
if you have one of the
animation states highlighted,
specifically Run_Static,
you can change the speed
that the animation runs itself.
And so we're going to make
it a little faster
than the standard animation speed.
We'll make it about 1.5,
and then you can press Play.
And then we can really see
our Player running through the scene.
And they're so happy
because they're in the wilderness.
Now it's your turn.
[music]